uCosta Software Developer



contact

Largo Ferreira Lapa, 70 3Esq 4150 - 323 Porto Portugal

> **(**+351) 924 241 327 S rui.d.a.costa

ruidacosta in ruidcosta

languages

Portuguese mother tongue English & Spanish fluency French basic (A1)

programming

JavaScript, C++, PHP, Java, C#, PL/SQL, Pvthon, CSS & HTML5

frameworks

NodeJS, AngularJS, JQuery, Django

tools

Salite, MySal, Oracle, MongoDB, Git, SVN, Docker

presentation

A versatile and professional graduate software developer with 3 years of commercial experience. Worked with C++, C#, Javascript and PL/SQL on Windows environments. Unix and Unix-like user with 6+ years of personal experience.

A proven ability to maintain and enhance company software with the aim of improving operational functionality in line with business requirement.

Able to work with any technology and to perform full software development life cycle activates.

Looking for a software developer opportunities that will allow me to work alongside an expert team of developers and on challenging projects in terms of technology and implementation. Thereby helping to drive my career progression to more seniors roles in the future.

experience

Full Time

2017-Now Natixis on Behalf of GFI - Software Developer

Work directly with business analysts, located in Paris and London, in order to implement client needs. Develop new features in existent applications (Squall and Booster) used by clients to book and manage contracts of SLB (Stock Lending and Borrowing) and TRS (Total Return Swaps). Create executables to generate specific client reports in csv files, and sending then by FTP or directly by email. Maintenance on existent applications, correcting bugs and optimising code. Second line support on Sophis Front Office - Equities and Commodities. Key Skills: C#, C++, Oracle Database, SQL Server, WPF, Windows Batch Scripting, SVN, TFS, Sophis, Equities, Commodities

Porto, Portugal

2013–2017 Finantech - Software Developer

Porto, Portugal Build functions and procedures on Oracle Databases for all company's trading systems. Add features, using C#, on a software designed to enable clients to configure their business rules. Fix bugs on trading server-side software, using C# and C++. Maintain existing libraries for communication interfaces with market data providers updated, using C++. Develop a Web Interface for all server side trading systems, using AngularJS and JQuery on front-end and C++ on backend. Server side application to insert real-time market data on a DB2 database system. Support clients in European and American financial markets. **Key Skills:** C++, C#, Oracle Databases, HTML, Javascript, JQuery, AngularJS, DB2 Databases, Fix Protocol, HTTP, REST API, Multi-Threading

Part Time

2006-2010 Freelancer - Backend developers

Develop back-end for some small websites in PHP. Key Skills: PHP, MySQL, Apache, HTML, Javascript

education

2010–2013 **Master** of Software Engineer Specialization in Network and Distributed Systems.

2006–2010 **Bachelor** of Software Engineer

University of Porto, Portugal

University of Porto, Portugal

interests

professional: software development, software design, web app creation, real-time computing, high-throughput computing, high-performance computing, parallel computing **personal:** riding motorcycle, playing music, cooking, trekking, spearfishing